Finding Aid for William Albright Papers 1962-1998
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Scores
  - William Albright Scores
    - The Great Amen, for flute and piano, 1992
      - sketch (Box 55)
      - annotated, photocopied manuscript (Box 14)
    - Halo, for large organ and metal instruments, 1978
      - notes (Box 55)
      - sketch (Box 55)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 14)
    - Heater: Saga for solo alto saxophone and band, 1977
      - sketch (Box 55)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 14)
    - Hymns (miscellaneous) (Box 14)
    - Imagined Quarter, an incentive for four percussionists, 1967
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 14)
    - In memoriam, 1983
      - manuscript (Box 14)
      - annotated, printed score [in The New Organ Album II, M. Haselbock and T.D. Sclee, eds. Austria: Universal Organ Edition, 1985] (Box 14)
    - Introduction, Passacaglia and Rondo Capriccioso: A concerto for tack piano, seven winds and percussion, 1974
      - notes (Box 14)
      - sketches (Box 55)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 14)
    - Jericho: Battle music for organ and trumpet, 1976
      - sketch (Box 55)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 14)
    - Juba, for organ, 1965
      - manuscript (Box 14)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 14)
      - printed score (Box 14)
    - The King of Instruments: A parade of music and verse for organ and narrator, 1978
      - sketch (Box 14)
      - manuscript (Box 14)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 14)
      - annotated, printed score (Box 14)
      - text for narrators (Box 14)
      - publicity poster (Box 14)
    - The Machine Age: A set of short piano pieces for our time, 1988
      (Movements: 1. The Ever-Blinking Eye, 2. Player-Piano on Broadway, 3. The Computer's Revenge (Scherzo), 4. Blues for Cristofori (Lullabye Pian'e Forte), 5. Robot Drummers from Hell, 6. Prayer)
      - notes (Box 55)
      - sketch (Box 55)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 14)
    - Marcia Funebre (Box 14)
      (see Concerto for Harpsichord and String Orchestra, Second Movement)
    - Marginal Worlds, for 12 instruments, 1968-1970
      - notes (Box 14)
      - sketch (Box 14)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 14)
    - Masculine-Feminine for orchestra, 1967
      (pseudonym for contest: "Frank Arthur, Student Composers' Awards")
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 47)
    - Mass in D for congregation, chorus, organ, tape, timpani, vibraphone, chimes, bells, glockenspiel, harmonicas, music boxes, etc., 1974
      - manuscript (Box 15)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 15)
    - Missa Brevis, for soprano or unison treble voices and organ 1996
      (Movements: 1. Kyrie, 2. Gloria, Intermezzo fantastico, 3. Sanctus, 4. Benedictus, 5. Agnus Dei)
      - research (Box 15)
      - notes (Box 15)
      - sketches (Box 55)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 15)
    - Mr. Cupid Machine for piano and voice 1971
      (words and music by William Albright and William Bolcom)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 15)
    - Movement, for woodwind quintet, undated
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 15)
    - New Leaves, for piano solo, Volume One 1991
      (Movements: 1. Spires, 2. Steering Wheel, 3. Valse triste, 4. Rivet Song, 5. Hymn)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 15)
    - Nine Pieces for Piano, 1962
      - manuscripts (Box 15)
    - Night Procession, for chamber orchestra, 1972
      - manuscript (Box 15)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 15)
    - Odds and Ends, for piano solo, 1991 (Box 15)
      (see New Leaves)
    - Old Tom Turpin (notes, sketches and lyrics), undated (Box 15)
    - Organbook: A set of pieces for pipe organ, 1967
      (Movements: 1. Benediction, 2. Melisma, 3. Fanfare, 4. Recessional)
      - sketch (Movements 2 only) (Box 15)
      - manuscript (Box 15)
      - annotated, printed score (Box 15)
      - articles (Box 15)
    - Organbook II 1971
      (Movements: 1. Night Procession, 2. Toccata Satanique, 3. Last Rites (with tape))
      - sketches (Box 15)
      - manuscript (Box 15)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 15)
      - printed score (Box 15)
    - Organbook III, 12 etudes for small organ, 1977-1978
      (Movements: Volume I: 1. Fanfare/Echo, 2. Curio I (trio), 3. Scherzo (Chimaera), 4. Jeu (for the stops), 5. Recitative-chorale, 6. Mountain, Volume II: 1. Underground stream, 2. Curio II (trio), 3. Basse de Trompette, 4. Jig for the feet (Totentanz), 5. Nocturne, 6. Finale--The Offering)
      - sketch (Box 55)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 15)
      - annotated, printed score (Box 15)
    - Organ Improvisation Themes, 1990
      - manuscript (Box 15)
    - Paroxysms, for clarinet and piano, undated
      - manuscript (Box 15)
    - Pax in Terra, mixed choir, a cappella with soprano and tenor soli, 1981
      - sketch (Box 55)
      - manuscript (Box 15)
      - printed score (Box 15)
    - Peace Pipe, for two bassoons, 1976
      - sketch (Box 55)
      - manuscript (Box 15)
    - Pianoagogo, 1965-1966
      - annotated, printed score (Box 15)
    - Pit Band, for alto saxophone, bass clarinet and pianoforte, 1993
      - sketch (Box 55)
      - manuscript (Box 16)
      - printed score (Box 16)
    - Pneuma, for organ, 1966
      - sketch (Box 16)
      - manuscript (Box 16)
    - Postcards from Kansas: Welcome to Interstate-70 for saxophone circa 1997
      Movements: A. Ribbon of Concrete, B. The Bridge, C. Motor Honey, D. Fines Doubled in Construction Zones, E. We Drive at Night, F. Road Kill, G. [missing?], H. Coda: Rest Stop, One Mile)
      - manuscript [incomplete?] (Box 16)
      - correspondence (Box 16)
    - Post Modern Fox Trot, for Glenn Watkins, 1996
      - notes (Box 16)
      - sketch (Box 55)
    - Pour Ceux Qui S'Aiment for voice and piano 1968
      (words by W.A. and E. Kurtz)
      - manuscript (Box 16)
    - Quintet, for flute, clarinet, violin, 'cello, harp, 1963
      - manuscript (Box 56)
    - Quintet for Clarinet and String Quartet, 1987
      (Movements: Movement One: The Wedge of Sighs, Movement Two: Theme and Variations)
      - notes (Box 16)
      - sketch (Box 56)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 16)
    - A Ragtime Lullaby for pianoforte, 1991
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 16)
    - Romance, for french horn and organ, 1981
      - sketch (Box 16)
      - reproduction of manuscript [unrevised] (Box 16)
      - revised reproduction of manuscript (Box 16)
    - Rustles of Spring, 1994 for flute, alto saxophone, violin, violoncello, pianofort, 1994
      (Movements: 1. Vernal Equinox, 2. The Wedding Dance [after Bruegel], 3. Solar Eclipse [in memoriam FSA])
      - notes (Box 56)
      - sketches (Box 56)
      - manuscript (Box 16)
      - annotated photocopy (Box 16)
      - printed score (Box 16)
    - Saints Preserve Us, Three "Etudes-prieres" for Solo Clarinet, circa 1987
      (Movements: 1. St. John of the Cross, 2. St. Joan at the Stake, 3. St. Vitus Dance)
      - sketches (Movements 1 and 3 only) (Box 56)
      - printed score (Box 16)
    - Salvos: Music for Seven Players, 1964
      - manuscript (Box 47)
    - Seven Deadly Sins, for flute, clarinet, string quartet, piano, and optional narrator 1974
      (Movements: 1. Wrath, 2. Vanity, 3. Lechery, 4. Gluttony, 5. Sloth, 6. Envy, 7. Greed, Grand Galop Finale [Dance of the Seven Sins])
      - sketch and manuscript (Box 16)
    - 1732 in memoriam Johannes Albrecht for solo organ, 1984
      (Movements: 1. Introduction, 2. The Family Albrecht in Germany, 3. William Penn's Invitation, 4. Exodus of the Palatines, 1683-1754, 5. Settlement of the Land: on the Schuylkill River in Berks County, 6. Frank to the Point of Rudeness, the Albright Clan Guards Honesty as a Cardinal Virtue, 7. An Evening Dance: the Thanks of the Family for their Divine Providence)
      - notes (Box 16)
      - sketches (Box 16)
      - annotated photocopies (Box 16)
      - annotated proofs (Box 16)
    - Shadows, eight serenades for guitar 1977
      (Movements: 1. Open, 2. Tierra [Dance], 3. Nights, 4. Spirits, 5. Lullaby, 6. Days, 7. Taranta [Dance], 8. Close)
      - sketch (Box 56)
      - manuscript (Box 16)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 16)
      - printed score (Box 16)
    - Shepherd of All Who Inhabit the Earth for organ and voice (text by Jeffrey Rowthorne), 1987
      - manuscript (Box 16)
    - Six New Hymns for unison chorus and organ, 1974-1983
      (Movements: 1. Vini sancte spiritus, 2. When Jesus Died to Save Us [version 1], 3. When Jesus Died to Save Us [version 2], 4. By Gracious Powers, 5. Look There! The Christ, 6. The Lord's Prayer)
      - sketches (Movements 3, 4, and 5 only) (Box 16)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 16)
      - printed score (Box 16)
    - Sleight of Hand Rag, 1988
      (from Three Novelty Rags) arrangement for orchestra
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 17)
    - Sonata for Alto Saxophone and Piano 1984
      (Movements: 1. Two-Part Invention, 2. La follia nuova: a lament for George Cacioppo, 3. Scherzo "Will o' the wisp," 4. Recitative and Dance)
      - notes (Box 17)
      - sketches (Box 56)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 17)
    - Sonata for Oboe and Harpsichord, 1963
      - sketch (Box 17)
      - manuscript (Box 17)
    - A Song to David: for antiphonal choirs, soloists, organ, by Christopher Smart, 1983
      (Movements: 1. David, 2. Creation, 3. Virtue, 4. Adoration, 5. Creation and Redemption)
      - sketches (Box 56)
      - manuscript (Box 17)
      - annotated reproductions of manuscript (Box 17)
      - printed score (Box 17)
      - Manuscript of hymns (Box 56)
      - Copy of Smart's poem with Albright's notes (Box 17)
      - Notes, correspondence, and text (Box 17)
      - Recording notes and correspondence 1990-1995 (Box 17)
      - Engraving proofs and correspondence 1996 (Box 17)
    - Sphaera, for piano and computer generated four-channel tape, 1985
      - revised reproduction of manuscript (Box 56)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 17)
      - Recording notes (Box 17)
    - [composition for Sports Illustrated film: Fun and Games and Deeper Passions], 1975
      - notes (Box 18)
      - sketches (Box 18)
      - manuscripts (Box 18)
      - Script and correspondence 1975 (Box 18)
    - Stipendium Peccati, for organ, piano and percussion, 1973
      - notes (Box 56)
      - sketch (Box 18)
      - manuscript (Box 18)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 18)
      - annotated, printed score (Box 18)
    - Stoptime for George's Birthday [George Rochberg] (Box 18)
      (see Four Dance Tributes)
    - Sweet Sixteenths: a cakewalk for clarinet, trombone, violoncello, piano, 1980
      - manuscript (Box 18)
    - Sweet Sixteenths: a classy rag for piano, 1975
      - manuscript (Box 18)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 18)
      - printed score (Box 18)
    - Sweet Sixteenths: a concert rag for organ, 1975
      - manuscript (Box 18)
      - printed score (Box 18)
    - Symphony for Organ, with percussion (or pre-recorded tape) 1986
      (Movements: 1. Lento, Maestoso, Lento; Molto ritmico; Lento; 2. Cantilena; 3. Tarantella macabra; 4. Ritual)
      - notes (Box 56)
      - sketch (Box 56)
      - annotated and revised reproductions of manuscript (Box 18)
      - percussion part (Box 18)
      - printed score (Box 18)
    - Take That, for 4 drummers with 16 drums, 1972
      - notes (Box 56)
      - sketches (Box 56)
      - annotated, photocopied score (Box 18)
      - printed score (Box 18)
    - Take Up the Song, for mixed choir, soprano solo and piano, 1986
      - sketch (Box 56)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 18)
      - engraving proofs [incomplete] (Box 18)
      - printed score (Box 18)
    - That Saxophone Rag (arrangement), by Sylvan Grosner and Rowland Fixel, 1976
      - sketch (Box 18)
      - photocopied score (Box 18)
    - That Sinking Feeling (morceau de concours), 1982
      - sketch (Box 56)
      - printed score (Box 18)
    - Three Anonymous Lyrics, for soprano, piano, clarinet and cello 1963
      (Movements: 1. Lenten is Come, 2. Lines from Love Letters, 3. This World's Joy)
      - manuscript (Box 56)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 56)
    - Three New Chestnuts, for two harpsichords, 1986
      (Movements: 1. Liebestraum, 2. Air on the G String, 3. Flight of the Bumble Bee)
      - notes (Box 18)
      - sketch (Box 56)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 18)
    - Three Novelty Rags for piano [written with William Bolcom]), 1968-1969
      (Movements: 1. Sleight of hand or "Legerdemain rag," 2. Burnt fingers a characteristic two-step, 3. Brass knuckles)
      - sketch (Movement 1 only) (Box 18)
      - manuscript and printed score (Box 18)
    - Three Original Rags: piano solo 1967-1968
      (Movements: 1. On the Lamb, 2. The Queen of Sheba, 3. Onion Skin)
      - sketch (Movement 3 only) (Box 18)
      - manuscript (Box 18)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 18)
      - printed score (Box 18)
    - Tic: a spectacle for two groups of performers, soloist, films, and tape, 1967
      - manuscript (Box 18)
    - Tower of Babel: Rag and Two-Step after Bruegel, undated
      - sketch (Box 56)
    - Two Pieces for Nine Instruments 1965
      (Movements: 1. Quick Getaway, 2. Polemics)
      - manuscript (Box 47)
    - Valley of Fire for sax quartet and organ, 1989
      - sketches (Box 56)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 18)
    - Vision for voice, (text by Don West), undated
      - manuscript (Box 18)
      - annotated photocopies (Box 18)
    - Whistler: Three Nocturnes for organ and organists' assistant 1989
      (Movements: 1. Chelsea Snow, 2. Falling Rocket, 3. Nocturne in Blue and Silver)
      - notes (Box 56)
      - photocopied sketches [incomplete?] (Box 56)
    - Commission notes and sketches 1997-1998 (Box 18)
    - Unidentified and miscellaneous sketches undated
      - 3 folders (Box 19)
      - 4 folders (Box 56)
    - Arrangements for classwork undated (Box 19)
  - William Albright Parts
    The sub-series William Albright Parts contains, minimally described, the part music available in the collection for individual instruments.
    - Abiding Passions for Woodwind Quintet (Box 19)
    - Beulahland Rag (Box 58)
    - Brass Tacks--Ragtime March (Box 19)
    - Chasm: Symphonic Fragment (Box 19)
    - Concerto for Harpsichord and String Orchestra (Box 20)
    - Cross of Gold: music-theater for actors, choir and musicians (Box 20)
    - Fantasy-Etudes for Saxophone Quartet (Box 20)
    - Foils for Wind Ensemble (Box 20)
    - Frescos (clarinet part) (Box 20)
    - The Great Amen, for flute and piano (flute part) (Box 20)
    - Heater: Saga for solo alto saxophone and band (Box 21)
    - Night Procession, for chamber orchestra (Box 21)
    - Pit Band, for alto saxophone, bass clarinet and pianoforte (Box 21)
    - Quintet for Clarinet and String Quartet (Box 21)
    - Salvos: Music for Seven Players (Box 58)
    - Seven Deadly Sins, for flute, clarinet, string quartet, piano, and optional narrator (Grand Galop Finale) (Box 21)
    - Sweet Sixteenths: a cakewalk for clarinet, trombone, violoncello, piano (Box 21)
    - Two Pieces for Nine Instruments (Quick Getaway--String Bass part) (Box 21)
  - Piano Music
    The next three sub-series--Piano Music, Organ Music and Various Composers--contain the unpublished or annotated scores from Albright's collection of works by his friends, teachers and students. The three divisions retain Albright's original arrangement, though Various Composers contains pieces for the piano and organ as well as the first two. One possible reason for the separation of these particular piano and organ pieces is that these are the works that he performed or planned to perform--many of the scores are annotated, and many of the titles are listed in his programs.
    - Ashwander, Donald and Matthew Davidson
      - Voodoo Queen: A Rag, 1992 (Box 22)
    - Blake, J. Hubert "Eubie"
      - Blue Rag in Twelve Keys, 1919 (Box 22)
      - " Eubie Boogie" Rag, undated (Box 22)
      - Chant Sans Paroles, copyright, 1970 (Box 22)
      - Kitchen Tom, 1917 (Box 22)
      - The Baltimore Todalo, copyright, 1970 (Box 22)
      - Brittwood Rag, copyright, 1970 (Box 22)
      - Dictys on 7th Ave, copyright, 1970 (Box 22)
      - Charleston Rag, undated (Box 22)
        (formerly called Sounds of Africa)
        (annotated)
      - Dream Rag, by Jessie Picket (arrangement), undated (Box 22)
    - Bolcom, William
      - The Walk from the Garden of Eden, 1969 (Box 22)
    - Borroff, Edith
      - Tatterdemalion: A Rag for a Wonderful History Class, 1972 (Box 22)
    - Chatman, Stephen
      - Bittersweet Rag 1977 (Box 22)
        (signed by composer)
    - Curtis-Smith, C
      - Meandering Rag, 1975 (Box 22)
    - Davidson, Matthew
      - A "Rag Suite" for Piano Solo: Three Elusive Rags, 1989-1990 (Box 22)
    - Foley, David
      - Ragtime Reflection, 1972 (Box 47)
    - Hines, Carl (?)
      - A Monday Date (?), undated (Box 22)
    - Hodkinson, Sydney
      - A Little Ragchime Music, 1981 (Box 22)
    - Johnson, James P
      - "The Symphonic Jazz of James Johnson" recording
        - Notes, clippings, music fragments (Box 22)
      - April in Harlem from Harlem Symphony copyright, 1944 (Box 22)
      - Eccentricity Waltz arranged by W.A., undated (Box 22)
      - Carolina Shout, circa 1921 (Box 22)
        (transcribed by W.A.)
      - Yamekraw (A Negro Rhapsody) copyright, 1928 (Box 22)
      - Snowy Morning Blues undated (Box 22)
    - Joplin, Scott
      - "Whatever Happened to Ragtime?" by W.A., William Bolcom and Dick Hyman, Kaufman Concert Hall 1996
        - Program (Box 22)
        - Script (Box 22)
        - Music
          - Rag-Time Dance: A Stop-Time Two Step, undated (Box 22)
          - Wall Street Rag copyright, 1909 (Box 22)
          - The Crush Collision March copyright, 1896 (Box 22)
          - Maple Leaf Rag copyright, 1899 (Box 22)
          - Peacherine Rag copyright, 1901 (Box 22)
          - Sun Flower Slow Drag: Rag Time Two Step with Scott Hayden copyright, 1901 (Box 22)
          - Weeping Willow: A Rag Time Two Step, copyright, 1903 (Box 22)
          - Palm Leaf Rag, copyright, 1903 (Box 22)
          - The Sycamore copyright, 1904 (Box 22)
          - The Chrysanthemum: An Afro-American Intermezzo, copyright, 1904 (Box 22)
          - Rose Leaf Rag: A Ragtime Two Step copyright, 1907 (Box 22)
          - Gladiolus Rag, copyright, 1907 (Box 22)
          - Heliotrope Bouquet: A Slow Drag Two Step with Louis Chauvin, copyright, 1907 (Box 22)
          - Sugar Cane: A Ragtime Two Step copyright, 1908 (Box 22)
          - Pine Apple Rag copyright, 1908 (Box 22)
          - Fig Leaf, copyright, 1908 (Box 22)
      - The Crush Collision March copyright, 1896 (Box 22)
      - Harmony Club Waltz copyright, 1896 (Box 22)
      - Combination March copyright, 1896 (Box 22)
      - Swipesy Cake Walk, 1900 (Box 22)
        (with Arthur Marshall)
      - The Augustan Club: Waltzes copyright, 1901 (Box 22)
      - Sun Flower Slow Drag: Rag Time Two Step copyright, 1901 (Box 22)
        with Scott Hayden
      - Cleopha: March and Two-Step copyright, 1902 (Box 22)
      - March Majestic copyright, 1902 (Box 22)
      - Something Doing: A Ragtime Two Step copyright, 1903 (Box 22)
      - Bethena: A Concert Waltz copyright, 1905 (Box 22)
      - The Rose-bud March copyright, 1905 (Box 22)
      - Binks' Waltz copyright, 1905 (Box 22)
      - Antoinette: March and Two-Step copyright, 1906 (Box 22)
      - Heliotrope Bouquet: A Slow Drag Two Step copyright, 1907 (Box 22)
      - Lilly Queen: A Ragtime Two-Step copyright, 1907 (Box 22)
      - Pleasant Moments: Ragtime Waltz copyright, 1909 (Box 22)
      - Felicity Rag: A Ragtime Two Step with Scott Hayden, copyright, 1911 (Box 22)
      - Kismet Rag with Scott Hayden, copyright, 1913 (Box 22)
    - Perone, James
      - Scott Free: A Rag for Piano, 1991 (Box 22)
      - Sudbury, Ontario 1990, 1990 (Box 22)
    - Sacks, Jonathan
      - Diablo's Inn 1981 (Box 22)
        (with note from composer)
    - Scott, James
      - Peace and Plenty Rag, copyright, 1919 (Box 22)
    - Steinhardt, Victor
      - Two Piano Pieces, 1985 (Box 22)
    - Utterback, Joe
      - Solace: Concert Jazz Improvisation for Classical Piano, 1990 (Box 22)
      - Dr. Joe's Long-fingered Ragtime Special, 1992 (Box 22)
    - Winkler, Peter
      - Do It! for 2 Jazz Pianists with Daniel Deutsch, 1973 (Box 22)
    - Wykes, Roger
      - Thornapple Rag circa 1994 (Box 22)
      - Plain Vanilla, circa 1994 (Box 22)
      - Bells and Whistles, circa 1994 (Box 22)
    - Unidentified
      - Hot Lips Honey, undated (Box 22)
      - The Dry Heave, undated (Box 22)
      - Ives: Improvisation X and Y (with note from composer), undated (Box 22)
    - Repertoire lists and notes undated (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 22)
  - Organ Music
    - Adler, Samuel
      - Fantasy on the Name Craighead (Box 23)
        (date illegible)
    - Aitken, Hugh
      - In Praise of Ockeghem for organ 1981 (Box 23)
    - Banfield, William C
      - Beach/Block: Fantasy for Organ and Readers, 1997 (Box 23)
    - Bassett, Leslie
      - Liturgies: Organ 1980 (Box 23)
    - Bates, D.S
      - Till Then, 1973 (Box 23)
    - Bayer, Michael
      - Figures, undated (Box 23)
      - Mephisto Waltz, undated (Box 23)
    - Bielawa, Herbert
      - The Organ Music of Herbert Bielawa: A Graphic Sampler, 1961-1996 (Box 23)
    - Borishansky, Elliot
      - Billwerder Moorfleet solo for organ, 1971 (Box 23)
    - Brons, Carel
      - Prismen for organ, 1967 (Box 23)
    - Buczynski, Walter
      - Miserere (organ part), undated (Box 23)
    - Burt, George
      - Variations for Organ and Orchestra undated (Box 48)
        (commissioned by William Albright)
    - Cacioppo, Curt
      - di cibo celeste, 1992 (Box 57)
    - Cacioppo, George
      - Dream Concert for Organ, Voice(s) and Small Percussion Orchestra undated (Box 23)
    - Cage, John
      - Souvenir, undated (Box 23)
    - Callaway, Ann
      - Paraphrasis, 1981 (Box 23)
    - Campanelli, Richard
      - And There Shall Come a Dark Angel, 1979 (Box 23)
    - Carlson, John
      - Soliloquy Scene for Organ, 1967 (Box 23)
    - Castiglioni, Niccolo
      - Sinfonie Guerriere et Amorose 1967 (Box 23)
    - Childs, Barney
      - The Edge of the World: bass clarinet and organ, 1981 (Box 23)
    - Chi-sun Lee, Chihchun
      - Testify! for Organ Solo, 1997 (Box 23)
    - Copland, Aaron
      - Episode 1941 (Box 23)
    - Crawford, Thomas
      - Canto II: Ashes of Rose, 1978 (Box 23)
    - Crumb, George
      - Pastoral Drone for organ 1982 (Box 23)
    - Curtis-Smith, C
      - Masquerades for Organ 1978 (Box 23)
        (dedicated to William Albright; annotated)
      - Variations on "Amazing Grace," 1983 (Box 23)
      - [Untitled] circa 1978 (Box 23)
        (includes note from composer)
    - Decker, Pamela
      - Fantasy and Fugue on a Tone Row, 1978 (Box 23)
      - Nightsong and Ostinato Dances for Organ, 1992 (Box 23)
      - Passacaglia for organ, 1980 (Box 23)
    - Dupre, Marcel
      - Cortege et Litanie pour orgue et orchestre, 1924 (Box 23)
      - G.F. Haendel: Seize Concertos pour Grand Orgue, 1937 (Box 23)
    - Durufle, Maurice
      - Suite pour Orgue, 1934 (Box 23)
    - Faxon, George
      - Roller Coaster (arrangement), by Louis Bush and Milon DeLugg, undated (Box 24)
      - Tribute to Duke Ellington, undated (Box 24)
    - Feldman, Morton
      - Principal Sound for organ solo, 1981 (Box 48)
    - Felciano, Richard
      - Ekagrata for organ, 2 drummers and electronic tape, circa 1972 (Box 24)
    - Finney, Ross Lee